Alejandro Gómez

Full Stack Developer focused on building products with good user experience

⊕ Mérida, México

alejandro@gomezarceo.mx • https://www.linkedin.com/in/alejandrogomezarceo/

About me

+15 years working with web technologies, particularly in Front-End in the last few years. I've been working with companies that have aided the growth of entrepreneurs, small and medium-sized businesses through the services they offer, from A/B testing, online reservation applications, and programmatic advertising. As a Software Engineer, I do my best to build high-quality web products, getting involved in all stages of development, such as project planning, product specifications, interface design, system design, testing, implementation, and the CI/CD pipeline.

Work Experience

Freestar May 2022 - Aug 2023

Front End Developer

Worked as a Front End developer to maintain and bring new features to their Main Dashboard, used for their internal operations. Made the next generation of their Public Dashboard that contained rich data reports and a better user interface that could help publishers administrate their ads inventory

Spot2Nite Jul 2021 – Apr 2022

Full Stack Developer

Worked with their internal API to maintain and bring new features. Integrated recreation.gov API to their reservations search engine. Built their first Public Reservation Web App

Convert Jan 2016 – Jun 2021

Front End Developer

Worked and grew along with the company for 5 years, contributing to their Web App evolution over that period. Built 3 generations of their User Interface, on every upgrade adding and pivoting features according to the market needs. Contributed to reach the company's 100K MRR goal by implementing the UI features the product needed at the time. Contributed to enforce GDPR compliance in the App ecosystem. Introducing coding standards and best practices to the team. Helped to build the first draft of the development culture of the company

Method Exists

Jan 2014 – Aug 2015

Full Stack Developer

Collaborated to develop a data—rich application that had to be capable of delivering vast amounts of data to be displayed and edited in real time using web sockets. We had to build Web Forms that contained several complex fields per page

Convert Nov 2012 - Apr 2013

External Consultant

Built the first generation of Convert's Single Page Application as an external consultant. This UI revamp introduced a fresh style and a more responsive experience to their customers

Wontonmedia Oct 2010 – Nov 2012

Web Developer

Built a CMS that was sold as a product to manage photo and video galleries for content network in the adult industry

DTraveller Jan 2009 - Sep 2010

Senior Software Engineer

Being responsible for keeping DTraveller's e-commerce applications up to date and running. Built integrations with local payment gateways services for the e-commerce solutions.

Education

Instituto Tecnológico de Mérida

2000 - 2005

Computer Systems Engineering

Projects

The Oneliner • •

A random joke comedian, made with Remix, hosted in Vercel, and loading pictures from the Unsplash API

Remix Side Project
Learning CI/CD in Vercel

The Broker • 🕥

A a lightweight UI to display data from the Marketstack API. You can use it with your own Marketstack API keys to view general data on your web browser. Give the project a star if you like it.

NextJs Side Project
API data display

Paisania •

A platform that wants to connect travellers with small communities within Spain. We are advocates that a conscious travel experience is about connecting with people, and being respectful with the place we're guests in

Lean Startup Conscious business
Connecting with people

Skills

